Shreyas/Shey Garga

Data Analyst

CONTACT

PHONE

703-986-6648

MAIL

garga.shreyas@gmail.com

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/shreyasgarga

GITHUB

https://github.com/sheygarga

TECHNOLOGY

PYTHON

SQL

HTML/CSS

JAVASCRIPT

MACHINE LEARNING/BIG DATA

ADVANCED EXCEL

JAVA

SKILLS

- DATA WRANGLING
- GRAPHING/CHARTING
- SOCIAL MEDIA MINING
- SQL/NoSQL (MONGODB) APP BUILDING
- WEB SCRAPING
- WEB DEVELOPMENT
- GEO MAPPING
- INTERACTIVE VISUALIZATION
- STATISTICAL ANALYSIS WITH R
- TABLEAU/POWERBI

Summary

Driven data analyst with a Bachelor's in Neuroscience and experience in business and social analytics. Has created numerous automated and responsive data analytics applications and solutions to identify, analyze, and interpret trends and patterns. Excellent research and analytical skills. Gamer, Twitch streamer, guitarist, and black belt in Tae Kwon Do.

Professional Experience

Avyuct

Herndon, VA

Developer and Data Analyst

Dec 2017 - Current

- Helping create the running model for sentiment analysis
- Assisting with the creation of the analytics model for predictive analysis and recommendation
- Handling algorithms in the Deep Learning team to create neural networks and models

Garga Insurance

Centreville, VA

Sep 2017 - Nov 2017

Social Media Coordinator

- Manage social media marketing using outlets such as Facebook, Tweeter, LinkedIn etc.
- Generate and/or find pertinent information and pictures to post content.
- Responsible for promoting posts and increasing online visibility

Behavioral Care Services

Gainesville, VA

Office Manager

Jun 2010 - Sep 2017

- Developed company web site, implemented search engine optimization. Responsible for website traffic
 analysis and google AdWords optimization.
- Established the processes for scheduling, collaboration and document sharing using Google applications
- Maintain and support network, hardware and software at the office.
- Handle operations of the practice including communicating with clients and insurance companies

Projects

My time at George Washington University has given me experience in full stack development of data analytic applications and solutions to make decisions, identify areas of improvement, and explore data for insight. Learnt the following technologies:

| Python | Pandas, Numpy, SciPy, MatPlotLib APIs, Tweepy, Vader, Seaborn, PySpark |
|----------|--|
| Database | SQL and noSQL databases such as MySQL and MongoDB and manipulated them with |
| | SQLAlchemy and Flask for web-scraping |
| Web | HTML, CSS and Javascript frameworks such as: Bootstrap, Plotly, ChartJS, JQuery, D3, Node, |
| | Agile, React, Leaflet, Carto |
| Big Data | TensorFlow, Spark, Hadoop, NLP, MRJob, Keras, SKLearn, |

My projects include:

- Python analysis of the Thomas Fire and the social media sentiment around Los Angeles
- Pandas data analysis for provided CSV files
- Live updating dataframe and graph for news sentiment analysis
- Live updating SQL app that can isolate vacation dates for Hawaii based on weather averages
- Web dashboard based on the global weather averages using Javascript, HTML, and Bootstrap
- Heroku-deployed app for analysis on given dataset alongside a resting API using Javascript.
- Responsive d3 and plot.ly based Javascript dashboard to show citation data for journalism
 Live updating, Heroku-deployed, Python and Javascript-based web app to display information about solar energy and skin cancer rates at the state level.

Education

George Washington University

Data Analyst/Data Visualization Certificate Program Oct 2017 – Apr 2018

George Mason University

BS of Neuroscience

Aug 2013- Dec 2017